Peter Smith Papers
Peter Smith Papers
- Business and land files
  - Land documents
    - Surveyor's documents
      - Charlotte River and Byrne's Patent (Box 19)
        - Charlotte River and Byrne's Patent survey, 1800-1805 (Box 20)
        - "A Resurvey & Subdivision of Lots in Charlotte River Patent. Made for Peter Smith, John Jacob Astor, and William Laight Esqs. in 1804 by Ch. C. Brodhead. Also surveys made in 1806", 1804-1806; book 1, north side of river; book 2, south side of river (Box 20)
        - "Surveys in Charlotte River Patent Made 1828, by James Frost" (Box 20)
        - "[Benjamin] Overbagh's Field Book No. 1," Byronville, for a survey of Charlotte River Patent, 1831 (Box 20)
        - "Hen[ry] Vrooman's Survey at Ch[arlotte] Riv[er] Pat[ent]", undated (Box 20)
      - New Petersburgh
        - "Field Book of the out Bounds of New Petersburgh, Surveyed in 1793," [J. Annin,] surveyor, for lands leased from the Oneida Indians (Box 20)
        - Survey of New Petersburgh, 1799 (Box 20)
        - "Field Notes of 7 Lots in the Late Oneida Reservation. Resurveyed and Subdivided in Oct, 1803 for Peter Smith by W. Hammond" (Box 20)
        - "Field Book of six Lots of Land in 1st. Allotment, Petersburgh, as run around and subdivided in August 1800 by W. Hammond for Peter Smith Esq.," Book 1 (Box 20)
        - "Field Book of Lot No 44, in the first Allotment, No. 29, in the second Allotment & Nos. 5, 6, 11, 17, 25, 26 & 35 in the 3rd Allotment of N. Petersburgh Surveyed & Subdivided in Sept., 1800 by W. Hammond for P. Smith Esq.," Book 2 (Box 20)
        - "Field Book Containing a description of the boundaries & quality of 26 Lots of Land in New Petersburgh, as Surveyed, Subdivided &c. in the Year 1801 for Peter Smith Esq, by Werden Hammond," Book 3, 1801-1811; also includes surveys by Enos Cushing (Box 20)
        - "Field Book Containing a description of the boundaries & quality of 67 Lots of Land in New Petersburgh, as Surveyed in April & May, 1802 for Peter Smith Esq. by Werden Hammond," Book 4 (Box 20)
        - "Fieldbook of sundry Lots surveyed in 2d, 3d & 4th allottments, New Petersburgh in Sept., 1802, for Peter Smith Esq. by Werden Hammond," Book 5 (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous material
        - Maps for surveyed lands, 1805-1850; undated; 2 folders (Box 20)
        - New York State Treasurer's receipts for land payments, 1802-1836; 3 folders (Box 21)
        - Surveyor's notes, 1811-1842; undated (Box 21)
  - Legal documents
    - Agreements on land purchases
      - A-P, circa 1799-1837; 16 folders (Box 21)
      - R-Y, circa 1799-1837; 7 folders (Box 22)
    - Bonds
      - [General], 1792-1831; 17 folders; not all years are represented (Box 22)
      - [General], Jan-Oct 1832; 8 folders (Box 22)
      - [General], Nov-Dec 1832; 3 folders (Box 23)
      - [General], Mar-Nov 1833; 8 folders (Box 23)
      - [General], Nov 1833; 2 folders (Box 24)
      - [General], 1834-1836; 4 folders (Box 24)
      - Peter Smith to the treasurer of the State of New York (missing as of July 1978), 1792-1836 (Box 24)
      - Peter Smith to others, 1792-1832 (Box 24)
      - Others to Peter Smith, 1796-1836 (Box 24)
    - Charges to the Grand Jury, 1800-1821; 3 folders (Box 24)
    - Contracts for land sales
      - General, 1816-1821; 6 folders (Box 25)
      - Lists of contracts made, circa 1814 (Box 25)
    - Deeds and indentures
      - [General], 1772-Oct 1795 (Box 25)
      - [General], Nov 1795-1803 (Box 26)
      - [General], 1803-1816 (Box 27)
      - [General], 1817-1823 (Box 28)
      - [General], 1826-1837 (Box 29)
    - Leases
      - Miscellaneous, 1800-1839; 4 folders (Box 29)
      - "Memo of Leases. Charlotte River Patent. Rents due and paid. John Jacob Astor, William Laight and Peter Smith", 1804-1840 (Box 29)
      - "Memo of Leases In Byrne's Patent, Rents due & paid. John Jacob Astor, William Laight & Peter Smith", 1801-1829 (Box 29)
    - Mortgages, 1809-1830 (Box 29)
    - Powers of attorney, 1801-1835 (Box 29)
    - Promissory notes, 1790-1831 (Box 29)
    - Suits, legal, 1790-1839; 5 folders (Box 29)
    - Summonses and complaints, 1799-1830 (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous legal documents, 1791-1837; undated; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Subject files
    - Grindstone business, 1814-1826 (Box 30)
    - Oneida Nation lease to Peter Smith; petition to State of New York; affidavit of Isaac Rappalye re. petition, 1793 (Map-case 68)
    - Partnership with John Jacob Astor and William Laight
      - Financial papers, 1823-1837 (Box 30)
      - Land records, undated (Box 30)
      - Legal papers
        - Miscellaneous, 1795-1835 (Box 30)
        - Agreements, 1799-1829; 2 folders (Box 30)
        - Bonds, 1800-1829 (Box 30)
        - Deeds and indentures, 1804-1824 (Box 30)
        - Leases, 1809-1831 (Box 30)
        - Powers of Attorney, 1795-1823 (Box 30)
        - Promissory notes, 1809-1811 (Box 30)
        - Suits, 1811; undated (Box 30)
    - Sir William Johnson's will in a contemporary copy, and related documents, 1763-1798 (Box 30)
- Writings
  - Journal, "Tour Northward, commence at Albany, July 15, end at Johnstown, Aug 17, 1822," in the handwriting of Peter Smith (Box 30)
  - Printed material, 1798-1821 (Box 30)
  - Verse in the handwriting of Peter Smith, undated (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous items in Smith's handwriting, undated (Box 30)
- Maps
  Maps are listed in a separate cartobibliography. (WARNING: This file is quite large and may take some time to download/open.)